各位朋友  大家好
Everyone, what's up?
我是Rob Dodson
It's Rob Dodson.
欢迎回到第二季的Polycast
Welcome back to season two of "Polycast."
在今天的一集中  我们来看一下
In today's episode, we're going to be looking
自动绑定的template元素
at the auto-binding template element.
这是一个不为大多数人所知的标签之一
It's one of those tags that not a lot of people know about,
但对于构建你的应用却有很大的帮助
but it's super useful for wiring up your application.
让我们一起来看一下
So let's check it out.
如果你之前或多或少接触过web组件
So if you've worked with web components for a bit,
你可能已经认出这是新的template元素
you've probably already seen the new template element.
template元素具有一些非常酷的特性
The template element has a few really awesome features.
第一也是最重要的 你放入一个template元素的
First and foremost, any content that you place inside
任何内容都将被完全冻结
of a template is going to be completely inert,
这意味着我们放在这里的这个H1标签
meaning this H1 that we have right here is not
将不会在页面上显示出来  除非我们真正地
going to display on the page until we actually
获取这个template元素的结构并且将其释放出来
grab the guts of this template and stamp it out.
另外  任何需要
Also, any elements that you have which
外部资源的元素  比如一个图片标签
require external resources, like an image tag,
也都不会产生任何的HTTP请求
for instance, are not going to make any HTTP requests.
还有  如果你的template元素里面有脚本的存在
Also, if you have script inside of your template,
这些脚本也不会被执行  直到这些脚本
it's not going to execute, not until it's
在这个页面上被激活
stamped out to the page.
这里有一些十分便利的特性
Some really handy features there.
通常地  如果你想要显示这些内容
Now normally, if you want actually display that content
正如我说的  你需要使用一些Javascript来使
as I said, you're going to have use some JavaScript to get
这些内容展现到页面上
all the guts onto the page.
但是如果你正在使用Polymer  事实上你可以
But if you're using Polymer, you can actually
为你的template元素加一个属性
add an attribute to your template.
然后就可以设置你的template元素是自动绑定的
You can say that your template is auto-binding.
这将会
And what that's going to do is it's
把你的template元素转换为被认为是
going to turn your template into what's
一个类型扩展的自定义元素
known as a type extension custom element.
事实上  正在发生的事情就是Polymer
Basically, what's happening is Polymer
已经为这个元素确定了一个定义
has already defined the definition for this element.
实际上它加载了Polymer的库
It actually ships with the Polymer library.
所以当你启动你的应用
So when you boot up your application,
它就已经在那里并做好了被使用的准备
it's there and ready to use.
现在  你的自动绑定的template元素
Now, your auto-binding template is
将会立即携带它的所有内容
going to immediately take all of its content
并激活到页面上
and stamp it out the page.
不仅如此  实际上它还允许你
And what's more, it actually allows
使用绑定到这个内容上的数据
you to use data bindings with this content.
那么就让我来用一个例子来展示如何做到这些
So let me show you an example of how you do that.
这里我们已经准备好了一个模板元素
Here, we've got a template element,
而且其中我放了一个H1标签
and inside, I've just placed an H1 tag.
因为我设置了is参数的自动绑定属性
And because I have this, is auto-binding attribute,
所以我能借助数据绑定的威力
I know that I can leverage the power of data binding.
我要做的第一件事
So the first thing I'm going to do
就是把H1标签的内容替换成花括号
is replace the content of that H1 with curly braces
并且定义一个范围变量
and define a scope variable.
在这个例子中  我把这个变量命名为message
In this case, I'm going to call the variable message.
在另一处的JavaScript中
Elsewhere in my JavaScript, I can
我可以用querySelector选择模板元素
select the template element using querySelector,
然后为message变量提供一个值
and then provide a value for that message variable.
这个值就会被传递到我的H1标签
This value is then going to be piped right back to my H1
然后在页面上显示文本内容
and show up as the text content on my page.
好吧  我知道这是一个非常简单的例子
All right, I know this is a really simple example,
那么先切到我们的代码编辑器
so let's switch over to our code editor,
我们来试着写一些Polymer元素
and we can actually start wiring up some Polymer elements.
这里我有一个非常基础的应用程序结构
So here, I have a really basic application structure
使用了Core Drawer Panel以及一些元素
using core-drawer-panel and some of the elements
也就是我们在之前的一集中构建的
that we've covered in previous episodes.
如果你还没有相关文件  我在之前的节目中提供了链接
And I've got links to those previous episodes down
并把它们放到了视频介绍里面
in the show notes if you'd missed them.
现在如果我打开浏览器
Now if I pop open the browser to check out
检查页面的结构  你可以看到它确实很简单
the structure of this page, you can see that it's pretty plain.
我们已经有了一个core菜单和几个可以点击的按钮
We've got a core menu with a few buttons that we can click on,
在这里是我们应用的标题
and we've also got the title of our application up there.
目前为止什么都还没有发生
Now right now, nothing's really happening.
所以我想做的第一件有意思的事就是使用绑定的数据
So the first thing that I can do is change the title of my app
更改我应用的标题
using a data binding to make it a little more interesting.
回到我的编辑器  我创建一个模板
Back in my editor, I'm going to create a template
然后给它一个自动绑定的属性
and give it an auto-binding attribute.
我还要给它一个ID
I'm also going to give it an ID, so I
这样我就能在稍后的JavaScript中来调用它
can reference it later using JavaScript.
接着就直接把我应用中的所有内容剪切
And then I can just go and cut and paste all the content
然后粘贴到这个模板里面
for my application and drop it inside of this template.
接下来我找到写着My App的地方
Next, I'm going to go down to where it says My App
并且把内容替换成绑定的数据
and replace the content with a binding, which
我把这个数据绑定命名为heading
I'm going to call heading.
然后我打开我的app.js文件
Then I'm going open up my app.js file,
对我的模板使用querySelector
and I'm going to querySelector for my template using
并指定我们刚才设定好的ID
the ID that we set earlier.
同时调用我的自动绑定的template元素
I'm also going to reference to my auto-binding template.
就可以直接为那个heading变量赋值
I can just provide a value for that heading variable.
在这个例子中  我让它显示  Hello Polycasters
In this case, I'm going to make it say, "Hello Polycasters."
现在当我刷新浏览器中的页面
Now, when I refresh the page in my browser,
你就会看到应用的标题
you'll see that the title of the application
已经变成了  Hello Polycasters
has been updated to say, "Hello Polycasters."
就如同展示的这般酷炫  但是这个菜单
Now, that's kind of cool, but the menu
仍然没有在我们的应用程序中做任何事
itself still doesn't really do anything in our application,
所以我们接下来设置它
so let's change that next.
回到我的编辑器  我定义一个名叫selected的变量并赋值为0
Back in my editor, I'm going to set a selected value of zero.
这是我创建的
And this is, again, just another scope
另一个范围变量
variable that I'm creating.
我在index文件中找到core菜单
In my index file, I'll find my core menu
然后将这个原本赋值为0的固定值
and change its hard coded selected value, which
改为调用范围变量selected
right now is zero, to that scope variable called selected.
接着往下看到我页面中的container
And I'm also going to go down to the container for my page
这里就是放置各种各样的
where, right now, it just has some sort of generic filler
需要显示在页面上的内容
content that says site content.
我们来修改一些文本
I'll update that with some text, which
这些文本最终会被输出到页面上
is going to actually print out the page
这里我们使用一下那个范围变量selected
that we're looking at using that selected scope variable.
切回浏览器  我再次刷新页面
Switching back to the browser, if I refresh the page
然后点击我菜单上的不同元素
and start clicking on the different elements in my menu,
你会看到数字在变化
you'll see that the number is updating
这使我知道当前哪个页面被选中
to let me know which page is selected.
这里还有一些给你的专业建议
Now here is a little ProTip for you.
当你使用自动绑定的template元素的时候
As you're working with the auto-binding template,
如果你需要通过JavaScript访问其中的元素
if you need to access any of its contents using JavaScript,
你就需要监听它的模板绑定事件
you're going to want to listen for its template-bound event.
其原因在于自动绑定的template元素
And the reason is because the auto-binding template stamps
是异步地输出它的内容的
out all of its content asynchronously.
为了演示如何做到这些
So to demonstrate how to do this,
我们只需要在控制台中查看
I'm just going to log the core menu element itself
core菜单元素自身的日志
to my console.
实现的方式是首先给我的template元素
The way to do that is to first add an event listener
添加一个事件监听
to my template.
然后我将监听模板绑定事件
And I'm going to be listening for that template-bound event,
这样我就能知道内容什么时候被输出到页面
so I know when all the content has been stamped to the page.
接着  在回调函数中
Then, in the callback function, I'm
我只要再次调用core菜单
just going to grab a reference to the core menu,
因为我已经知道这是一个可用的文档元素
because now I know that it is in the document and available.
这样我们就向控制台输出了日志
And then I'm just going to log it out to the console.
回到Chrome
And I'm back in Chrome.
我刷新一下页面然后打开开发人员工具
I refresh the page and open up the dev tools.
你就可以看到下面
And you can see down here at the bottom,
core菜单的日志被立即输出
that core menu gets logged out immediately,
而且上方页面中的core菜单元素以高亮显示
and it highlights the core menu element on the page.
那么现在你应该已经准备好为你自己的应用
So now you're ready to go add data
添加数据绑定了
binding to your own application.
在下一集中  我将会把自动绑定的template元素
In the next episode, I'm going to combine
与一个称作core页面的元素相结合
the auto-binding template with an element called core pages,
这样我们就能真正地动态地改变
so we can actually dynamically swap around
我们应用中的内容
the content in our application.
敬请锁定我们的节目
Definitely stay tuned for that.
总之  感谢你的观看
As always, thank you so much watching,
我们下期节目再见
and I will see you next time.